<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Playgrounds &#8211; SG Snaps</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/playgrounds/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Preserving Precious Memories</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 03:12:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Volunteering Like No Other!</title>
		<link>/volunteering-like-no-other/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 01:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Redhill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflection and Recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Door-to-door]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HDB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neighbourhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo techniques]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playgrounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portraits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[6 months ago, since the day we had received our first photo contribution, it has been nothing but hard work for everyone in the SG Snaps team. Going through the thousands of beautiful memories that we have collected from our trusting contributors now brings us wonderful experiences from our collection drive. We cannnot say this any less: All the photographs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>6 months ago, since the day we had received our first photo contribution, it has been nothing but hard work for everyone in the SG Snaps team. Going through the thousands of beautiful memories that we have collected from our trusting contributors now brings us wonderful experiences from our collection drive. We cannnot say this any less: All the photographs that we have collected will not be possible without the efforts of the participating students who have stepped up to go door to door in the neighbourhoods with us.</p>
<p>For this blog entry, we recollect one of the best days with a group of 12 volunteers joining us at Redhill. The participating volunteers were the staff of the <a href="http://www.halogen.sg/">Halogen Foundation</a>, teamed together with students from CHIJ St Theresa&#8217;s Convent and Hwa Chong Institution. It was daunting, thinking how to coordinate 6 pairs of volunteers scattered in the neighbourhood, but we knew one thing for sure &#8211; that each of their participation will be unique with every resident they meet.</p>
<p>The volunteer experience at Singapore Snaps means a lot to us. We believe, for an individual who shares our vision and comes forward to work with us, every precious minute of their time counts. The best returns of volunteering will always be the learning and interaction in a social sphere where the public gathers to do good. Because of that, before we head out to the neighbourhoods to interact with the local residents, a warming-up briefing session with our volunteer team would be the key to a rewarding volunteer experience.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_03.jpg"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-814" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_01.jpg" alt="Khee Shi Hui_01" width="898" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_01.jpg 898w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_01-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 898px) 100vw, 898px" /></a></p>
<p>Each volunteer gets to introduce himself or herself in the quirkiest of ways &#8211; by recounting his or her first memory; the first thing you remember consciously. This is SG Snaps&#8217; unique way in getting to know everyone better. This part of the session is always filled with comical moments that even the shyest volunteer would join the conversation and have a good laugh.</p>
<p>Simply because SG Snaps is one project which is interested in excavating memories, being acquainted with our volunteers means learning their memories too. First memories are significant to us, because it is intimate and it signifies the beginning of our consciousness as an individual. We also had the honour of some volunteers bringing their own photo albums to share with the group. Looking through old photographs is one definite way of knowing a person better.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_05.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-818" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_05.jpg" alt="Khee Shi Hui_05" width="401" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_05.jpg 401w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_05-200x300.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 401px) 100vw, 401px" /></a></p>
<p>Most certainly, the most important aspect of our briefing session is appreciating and handling the old photographs. We prepare our volunteers to receive the photographs in an array of formats &#8211; from the ones pasted into adhesive albums, to the ones inserted in sleeves or even piled up in loose sheets. SG Snaps team member and photographer Samantha Tio, shared with the student volunteers the technicalities of handling photographic prints. She also shared her views on why images created during the era of analog cameras are important and relevant to us even today.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_06.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-819" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_06.jpg" alt="Khee Shi Hui_06" width="898" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_06.jpg 898w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_06-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 898px) 100vw, 898px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_10.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-821" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_10.jpg" alt="Khee Shi Hui_10" width="898" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_10.jpg 898w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_10-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 898px) 100vw, 898px" /></a></p>
<p>The students started out with great energies, and with positive attitudes they had managed to encounter some amazing finds. During this particular door-to-door collection drive in Redhill, we found our first hand-coloured photographs. For many of the young participants, it was the first time seeing anything like that. <a href="/excavating-the-modern-studio-portrait-in-singapore/">Read more about studio portrait trends from the 1950s-80s in our previous post.</a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_11.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-822" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_11.jpg" alt="Khee Shi Hui_11" width="898" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_11.jpg 898w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_11-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 898px) 100vw, 898px" /></a></p>
<p>What was also remarkable about that photograph was the handwritten message on the back in Chinese characters in calligraphic style, dating and addressing the portrait to a beloved. The photograph was taken and developed in 1967, and was addressed to the sender&#8217;s aunt. We later noticed more photographs with such personal messages. It was a trend then, to give a copy of the photo with accompanying text to relatives and friends, just like a postcard.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_12.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-823" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_12.jpg" alt="Khee Shi Hui_12" width="401" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_12.jpg 401w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_12-200x300.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 401px) 100vw, 401px" /></a></p>
<p>One of our youngest volunteer, Edison recounts how he was so delighted when an elderly resident had invited his group into his house. He described the house to be filled with incredible antiques and the series of portraits that he had kindly contributed for the project seemed to be dated to the early 20th century.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_12.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-820" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_07.jpg" alt="Khee Shi Hui_07" width="898" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_07.jpg 898w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Khee-Shi-Hui_07-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 898px) 100vw, 898px" /></a></p>
<p>Unfortunately not all the students managed to interest a resident to participate and contribute old photographs. Rejection is part of this learning process and it pushes us beyond of our comfort zones, humbling and motivating us continuously. We truly hope our volunteering students had learned beyond the textbooks, and benefited from their unconventional afternoon with <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sgsnaps">Singapore Snaps</a>.</p>
<p>Written by Samantha Tio</p>
<p>Edited by Tan Wei Keong</p>
<p>Photographs by Khee Shi Hui</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toa Payoh: From Marshland to Satellite Neighbourhood</title>
		<link>/toa-payoh-from-marshland-to-satellite-neighborhood/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 01:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Old Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflection and Recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toa Payoh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1970s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HDB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neighbourhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playgrounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queen Elizabeth II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tree god]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The energetic buzz of the Toa Payoh Central was extremely effecting and perfect for the first neighbourhood to kick-start our photo-collection drive at Singapore Snaps. Toa Payoh Central has every conveniences to suit the quintessential middle-class Singaporean lifestyle &#8211; a train station linked to a bus interchange, a cozy public library, and a wide selection of eateries ranging from coffee [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The energetic buzz of the Toa Payoh Central was extremely effecting and perfect for the first neighbourhood to kick-start our photo-collection drive at Singapore Snaps. Toa Payoh Central has every conveniences to suit the quintessential middle-class Singaporean lifestyle &#8211; a train station linked to a bus interchange, a cozy public library, and a wide selection of eateries ranging from coffee shops, food kiosks to fast food restaurants and all the ubiquitous food chains. There are also supermarkets, mega-stationery-shop, banks and rows of shops selling clothes, gadgets, services and what-nots.</p>
<p><em>Mdm Sisilia Tan and company posing for a picture by the sculpture found in Toa Payoh Town Park with the estate in the backdrop. Photo: Sisilia Tan</em></p>
<p>Also located here is the headquarters of our nation&#8217;s Housing Development Board (HDB).  Situating the headquarters here is extremely apt for being the first town to be built ground-up by the board in 1968. With a neighbourhood population of close to 116,000 people, it is not a surprise that the town centre will always be crowded with people, especially during the evenings and weekends.</p>
<p>Through chatting with the local residents, we discovered the urban legends and quaint histories of this neighbourhood.</p>
<p><strong>1. Urban legend goes that there was an immutable “Tree God” which fell in a storm in September last year.</strong></p>
<p>Every morning, the SG Snaps team strolled past the site where the “Tree God” used to be &#8211; on the way from the train station to the community library. We were told about the lightning strike that brought down the tree said to be over 100 years old. It is with this curiosity that we searched for the site to pay tributes.</p>
<p>Upon quizzing a few of the shop owners in the vicinity, we were directed to a tightly barricaded site that seemed dilapidated and uncared for. The emptiness of the space was a huge departure from our imagination of the tree with majestic bark and extensive branches that shaded the temple that was beneath it.</p>
<div id="attachment_664" style="width: 339px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Tree-God_National-Archives.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-664" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-664 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Tree-God_National-Archives.jpg" alt="A photo from the 1970s of the sacred tree and its temple at Toa Payoh Central. Photo: National Archives of Singapore" width="329" height="508" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Tree-God_National-Archives.jpg 498w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Tree-God_National-Archives-194x300.jpg 194w" sizes="(max-width: 329px) 100vw, 329px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-664" class="wp-caption-text">A photo from the 1970s of the sacred tree and its temple at Toa Payoh Central. Photo: National Archives of Singapore, Source: Singapore Press Holdings</p></div>
<p>The site did exude a mystical charm which was even more resonant when we learned of the strange occurrences when the new town was constructed in 1965: The bulldozers that were tasked to flatten the area malfunctioned when they approached the tree. Workers who tried to fell the tree had also died mysteriously. The town planners then had to alter the layout of the shop houses to accommodate the tree in the centre. Isn&#8217;t it interesting how our urban development can be shaped by mysticism and superstition?</p>
<p><strong>2. Toa Payoh Public Library was one of the earliest full-time library to open after Queenstown.</strong></p>
<p>The location, prior to the opening of the library, was the Games Village which housed athletes for the 7<sup>th</sup> South East Asian Peninsula Games. It was the first regional sporting event ever held in the country in 1973.</p>
<div id="attachment_656" style="width: 485px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Toa-Payoh.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-656" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-656" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Toa-Payoh.jpg" alt="Photo: Chan Lee Shan" width="475" height="674" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Toa-Payoh.jpg 540w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Toa-Payoh-211x300.jpg 211w" sizes="(max-width: 475px) 100vw, 475px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-656" class="wp-caption-text">A portrait at the fountain in front of Toa Payoh Community Library. Photo: Chan Lee Shan</p></div>
<p>Before the amphitheatre in the front of the library was built, there was a huge water fountain where many of the residents gathered for photographs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_659" style="width: 624px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-659" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-659 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-1024x680.jpg" alt="The SG Snaps team (from left) Gracie, Stacy and Wei Keong at the cozy booth on the second floor of Toa Payoh Community Library. Photo: SG Snaps" width="614" height="408" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-1024x680.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-300x199.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-1800x1200.jpg 1800w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-1280x850.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 614px) 100vw, 614px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-659" class="wp-caption-text">The SG Snaps team (from left) Gracie, Stacy and Wei Keong at the cozy booth on the second floor of Toa Payoh Community Library. Photo: SG Snaps</p></div>
<p>Toa Payoh Community Library has got to be one of our favourite libraries visited. The library was streaming continuously with visitors over the weekend. Besides being a conducive air-conditioned haven for our tired volunteers to catch their breaths, the library staff there were simply endearing. <a href="/sunny-days-an-offbeat-meeting-at-the-toa-payoh-public-library/">Uncle Sunny</a> is one of them, along with the counter staff who would climb up and down the stairs assisting our requests. Huiyi and Shao, from the Arts and Culture team of the National Library Board, were the ones who made our 3-weeks residence at the library possible. We missed the friendly cleaning aunties whom we grew close to and felt so sorry when we had to leave for another library.</p>
<p><strong>3. Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II visited the flats in Toa Payoh twice in 1972 &amp; 2006.</strong></p>
<p>Ask any long-staying resident for a historical anecdote of Toa Payoh and they will definitely mention the visit of Queen Elizabeth II. The lucky then-boy-now-man visited by the Queen in 1972 is Mr Jerome Lim, writer of the blog &#8216;The Long Winding Road&#8217; which reminiscent intimately the personal histories of growing-up in Singapore.</p>
<div id="attachment_666" style="width: 394px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/queen-elizabeth-visits-toa-payoh.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-666" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-666" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/queen-elizabeth-visits-toa-payoh.jpg" alt="Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II on the rooftop of Toa Payoh's VIP Flat at Blk 53 Lorong 5, during her visit in 1972. Photo: www.toapayoh.com" width="384" height="278" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/queen-elizabeth-visits-toa-payoh.jpg 384w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/queen-elizabeth-visits-toa-payoh-300x217.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 384px) 100vw, 384px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-666" class="wp-caption-text">Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II on the rooftop of Toa Payoh&#8217;s VIP Flat at Blk 53 Lorong 5, during her visit in 1972. Photo: www.toapayoh.com</p></div>
<p>The Queen had visited Mr Lim’s 3-room flat &#8211; a VIP Flat with a rooftop viewing gallery, which sounds like the Pinnacle@Duxton of the 1970s. She returned to the estate 34 years later in 2006 during her Diamond Jubilee tour of the world. There must be a certain nostalgia and pride that our country holds for our history of being colonised.</p>
<p><strong> 4. How can we not possibly mention? The Dragon Playground, of course.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_651" style="width: 529px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-651" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-651" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground-732x1024.jpg" alt="Photo: Seow Shin Horng" width="519" height="726" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground-732x1024.jpg 732w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground-214x300.jpg 214w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground.jpg 1040w" sizes="(max-width: 519px) 100vw, 519px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-651" class="wp-caption-text">Walking along the long &#8216;body&#8217; of the Dragon. Photo: Seow Shin Horng</p></div>
<p>I suppose, most heritage buffs in Singapore would know of the Dragon Playground along Lorong 6. The playground has become so iconic that it has inspired more replicas and reflections than the Merlion in the last 2 years.</p>
<div id="attachment_652" style="width: 567px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-652" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-652" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground-1024x730.jpg" alt="Photo: Seow Shin Horng" width="557" height="396" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground-1024x730.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground-300x213.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground-1280x913.jpg 1280w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground.jpg 1458w" sizes="(max-width: 557px) 100vw, 557px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-652" class="wp-caption-text">Digging sand with daddy at the Pelican Playground. Photo: Seow Shin Horng</p></div>
<div id="attachment_650" style="width: 480px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-650" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-650" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground-730x1024.jpg" alt="Photo: Seow Shin Horng" width="470" height="659" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground-730x1024.jpg 730w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground-213x300.jpg 213w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground.jpg 1046w" sizes="(max-width: 470px) 100vw, 470px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-650" class="wp-caption-text">The Dove Playground. Photo: Seow Shin Horng</p></div>
<p>The Dragon Playground was part of a series of animal-inspired playground designed by the HDB in the 1970s. Other motifs include the Pelican, Dove and Elephant etc. In the collection of photographs received from the public, there were many cute kids portraits taken at these playgrounds. It is no doubt that these playgrounds have a prominent place in the childhood memories of Singaporeans who grew up during that era. Though there is another dragon playground in Ang Mo Kio, it is the one in Toa Payoh that retains the sand pit. A sand-filled playground was a common structure in most neighbourhoods, before boring rubber matting replaced the sand. What&#8217;s the fun if you can’t throw sand into the eyes of your enemy/crush ?</p>
<p><strong>5. Toa Payoh used to be a farmland</strong>.</p>
<p>Part of the old Toa Payoh came alive when we spent an afternoon with Mdm Lim Mui Tiang, a resident of Toa Payoh. Mdm Lim recounted where the farms were, and how the HDB flat she&#8217;s living in was previously a hill flattened for the construction of the town. At the age of six, she helped at her family farm with the harvesting of vegetables and feeding of the poultry. By seven, she was bringing water from the well. Though we probably have heard similar stories from the earlier generations many times, it is hard to imagine the same kind of hardship for any children growing up in modern Singapore.</p>
<div id="attachment_667" style="width: 490px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ToaPayoh1967.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-667" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-667" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ToaPayoh1967.jpg" alt="ToaPayoh1967" width="480" height="339" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ToaPayoh1967.jpg 480w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ToaPayoh1967-300x211.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-667" class="wp-caption-text">Aerial view of Toa Payoh taken in 1967. Photo: www.toapayoh.com</p></div>
<p>Toa Payoh has come a long way from its earliest histories of being made up of marshland and plantations. The name “Toa Payoh” means “big swamp”  in the Hokkien dialect. Walking down the concrete paths, watching people sip coffee from Starbucks, families pushing their children around in strollers and pedestrians burying their heads in their devices, it must be really astounding to witness such tremendous change within a single lifetime.</p>
<p>Written by Samantha Tio<br />
Edited by Tan Wei Keong</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ways We Used to Play</title>
		<link>/ways-we-used-to-play/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 05:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Old Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playgrounds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Ways We Used to Play&#8221; is a theme that was rather evident when we looked through the photographs. Our collection is in no way an exhaustive representation of this theme, but it acts as a guide and builds on the other ways and games we used to play, which seem to have gained more popularity in our quest for nostalgia. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Ways We Used to Play&#8221; is a theme that was rather evident when we looked through the photographs. Our collection is in no way an exhaustive representation of this theme, but it acts as a guide and builds on the other ways and games we used to play, which seem to have gained more popularity in our quest for nostalgia.</p>
<div id="attachment_498" style="width: 372px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0083.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-498" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-498 " title="Child on rattan horse" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0083.jpg" alt="" width="362" height="498" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0083.jpg 2096w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0083-218x300.jpg 218w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0083-744x1024.jpg 744w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0083-1280x1761.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-498" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Koh Leh Kheng Serene</p></div>
<p>Did you have a rocking horse made of rattan when you were young? I vaguely remember having had one, though I cannot be completely sure – That’s the problem with memories, isn&#8217;t it?</p>
<p>Still, it’s incredible how toys used to be so simple yet did an excellent job of entertaining the young and keeping them occupied. These days, rattan shops selling handmade furniture still exist and it is possible to find a rocking horse such as this in Singapore, but they just aren’t as popular as they used to be.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-491 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/001-1.jpg" alt="001 (1)" width="633" height="452" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/001-1.jpg 2930w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/001-1-300x214.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/001-1-1024x731.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/001-1-1280x913.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 633px) 100vw, 633px" /></p>
<p>Many of us would fondly remember the sandy playgrounds that once littered our neighbourhoods. This giant spinning wheel of iron was a common feature in the playgrounds back in the days.</p>
<p>It was removed from modern playgrounds as it was deemed to be a little too dangerous, and I must admit, it can, for lack of a better description, spin out of control, when you have one too many overly enthusiastic and energy-pumped kids playing at the same time. So while it is with bitter sweetness that we look back on this play feature, I imagine it was removed for the better!</p>
<div id="attachment_492" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/007.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-492" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-492 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/007.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="447" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/007.jpg 3008w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/007-300x206.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/007-1024x704.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/007-220x150.jpg 220w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/007-1280x880.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-492" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Selina Selvarani</p></div>
<p>Yes, McDonald&#8217;s has been responsible for many children’s fond memories of playtime and birthday celebrations, and for fair reasons. This fast-food chain used to have allocated spaces for children to play, notably at King Albert Park and Kallang. The former branch no longer exists.</p>
<p>These days, it seems that McDonald’s no longer has play places within its eateries, and the almost legendary status of Ronald McDonald himself seem to be a rare sight too!</p>
<p>Do you know of any McDonald&#8217;s locations that still have play places with its mascot statue?</p>
<div id="attachment_493" style="width: 607px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0012_2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-493" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-493 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0012_2.jpg" alt="" width="597" height="457" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0012_2.jpg 2073w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0012_2-300x229.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0012_2-1024x783.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0012_2-1280x979.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 597px) 100vw, 597px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-493" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Lee Lim Mui Vivian</p></div>
<div id="attachment_494" style="width: 592px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0015.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-494" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-494 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0015.jpg" alt="" width="582" height="407" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0015.jpg 2997w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0015-300x209.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0015-1024x715.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0015-1280x894.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 582px) 100vw, 582px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-494" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Fu Yabo</p></div>
<div id="attachment_500" style="width: 576px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/00104.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-500" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-500 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/00104.jpg" alt="" width="566" height="406" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/00104.jpg 2914w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/00104-300x214.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/00104-1024x733.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/00104-1280x917.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 566px) 100vw, 566px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-500" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Koh Leh Kheng Serene</p></div>
<p>Yes, you&#8217;ve guessed it &#8211; Funfairs! This pirate boat was one of the fascinating rides at make-shift fairs that were set up in the neighbourhoods and shopping centres. We’re not quite sure of the period when these rides stopped becoming a feature in our environment, but they sure were adorable.</p>
<p>Have you taken a ride in one of these?</p>
<div id="attachment_497" style="width: 462px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a style="line-height: 1.5em;" href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0080.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-497" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-497 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0080.jpg" alt="" width="452" height="662" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0080.jpg 2091w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0080-204x300.jpg 204w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0080-698x1024.jpg 698w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0080-1280x1876.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 452px) 100vw, 452px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-497" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Chan Lee Shan</p></div>
<p>Still keeping to the nautical theme, this sure was one strange playground! Larger-than-life seashells, on land!<br />
Does anyone know where this was, and why they were placed there?</p>
<div id="attachment_495" style="width: 657px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0041.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-495" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-495 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0041.jpg" alt="" width="647" height="452" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0041.jpg 2994w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0041-300x209.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0041-1024x715.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0041-1280x893.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 647px) 100vw, 647px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-495" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Chan Lee Shan</p></div>
<p style="text-align: left;">Equally puzzling, though not quite as strange &#8211; We thought this might have been in Kallang, though we’ve been told it was in Sentosa. Either way, this pedal boat ride looks very stylish and safe. Just look at that contraption! It looks awesome isn’t it? It&#8217;s like a 1970’s version of a speed boat, albeit with the two silver torpedo at the bottom of the red seats. I wish these were still around and I wonder what happened to this ride!</p>
<div id="attachment_496" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0076.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-496" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-496 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0076.jpg" alt="" width="630" height="448" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0076.jpg 2917w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0076-300x213.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0076-1024x728.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/0076-1280x910.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-496" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Fu Yabo</p></div>
<p>Do you have other photographs of this theme that you’d like to share? Send us your photo and a short description at we@sgsnaps.com so that we can share them with everyone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
