<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Toa Payoh &#8211; SG Snaps</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/toa-payoh/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Preserving Precious Memories</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 03:12:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Seletar Camp Memories &#8211; A Homevisit with Mdm Saraswathi</title>
		<link>/seletar-camps-memories-a-home-visit-with-mdm-saraswathi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 01:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Old Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflection and Recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toa Payoh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Door-to-door]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hindu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kavadi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neighbourhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Procession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seletar camp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thaipusam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Free and open air movie screenings on the big grass patch at Seletar Camp was one of the fondest memories of Mdm Saraswathi. A bright smile lit up on her face as she was looking through the black and white photographs, which she had shared with us during a visit to her current home in Toa Payoh. These photographs gave [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Free and open air movie screenings on the big grass patch at Seletar Camp was one of the fondest memories of Mdm Saraswathi. A bright smile lit up on her face as she was looking through the black and white photographs, which she had shared with us during a visit to her current home in Toa Payoh. These photographs gave us an insightful glimpse of her life inside the camp.</p>
<p>Top picture: Mdm Saraswathi with her first child, standing outside her block at the residential wing of the Seletar Camp. Photo Credit: Saraswathi</p>
<div id="attachment_927" style="width: 618px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Saraswathi.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-927" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" class=" wp-image-927" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Saraswathi.jpg" alt="Mdm Saraswathi with a stack of old photographs of Seletar Camp in her hands. Photo credit: SG Snaps" width="608" height="345" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Saraswathi.jpg 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Saraswathi-300x170.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 608px) 100vw, 608px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-927" class="wp-caption-text">Mdm Saraswathi with a stack of old photographs of Seletar Camp in her hands. Photo credit: SG Snaps</p></div>
<p>As a clerk to the Singapore Armed Forces, Mdm Saraswathi had lived in residential quarters at the military facility together with her family. She shared with us her family&#8217;s long history there, since the camp&#8217;s former days of being the largest British Royal Air Force base in the Far East. Built by the British in the 1920s, the camp became operational in 1928 and had housed staffs to the British Airforce. Aside from the British, the Malay and Indian community had made up majority of the staff. Her father, who was an Indian migrant, had worked for the British as a labourer, and her uncle as a supervisor.</p>
<div id="attachment_915" style="width: 574px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/00101.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-915" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-915" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/00101-1024x784.jpg" alt="A photograph of Mdm Saraswathi, her husband, first son and her two brother in her husband's quarters. Photo credit: Mdm Saraswathi" width="564" height="432" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/00101-1024x784.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/00101-300x229.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/00101-1280x980.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 564px) 100vw, 564px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-915" class="wp-caption-text">A photograph of Mdm Saraswathi, her husband, first son and her two brothers in her husband&#8217;s quarters. Photo credit: Saraswathi</p></div>
<p>The living quarters were located at the east side of the camp. Mdm Saraswathi described two different layouts of the quarters. Her husband was also a staff who lived in the bigger quarters, while she had grown up in the smaller one with her family &#8211; A three-room apartment consisting one hall, bedroom and kitchen. There were six apartments in a block, with toilets and water taps shared between all the families living there. She remembered how she needed to take her laundry and plates out to the public tap for cleaning. On the other hand, her husband&#8217;s house, where she had moved to after their wedding, had a private toilet, but the rent was higher.</p>
<p>&#8220;The rent for the three-room quarters (back then) was only $12 per month. For the bigger one, it was $20,&#8221; said Mdm Saraswathi.</p>
<p>In a photo taken right in front of the guardroom of the residential quarters, Mdm Saraswathi recounts how tightly guarded the facility was. Any of her relatives visiting the camp were required to report to the guard house, where she would have to produce her official pass in order to allow them onto premise. Public access into the camp was highly restricted, and any outsiders entering or leaving the camp were duly noted by the guards.</p>
<p>During Christmas, the British would hold celebrations for the military staff. Families would go to the clubhouse carrying coupons previously handed out to them, to collect goodie boxes filled with cakes and ice-creams for every member of each household. The clubhouse was also a place where families held meetings, as well as movie screenings hosted for the families.</p>
<p>&#8220;We would bring out big mats to lay on the grass and watch the movies for free from the big screen,&#8221; she quipped.</p>
<div id="attachment_922" style="width: 415px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/003.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-922" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-922" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/003.jpg" alt="Bride &amp; Groom - a photograph of Mdm Saraswathi's wedding held at a tent pitched on a field in Seletar Camp. Photo credit: Mdm Saraswathi" width="405" height="633" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/003.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/003-192x300.jpg 192w" sizes="(max-width: 405px) 100vw, 405px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-922" class="wp-caption-text">Bride &amp; Groom &#8211; A photograph of Mdm Saraswathi&#8217;s wedding held at a tent pitched on a field in Seletar Camp. Photo credit: Saraswathi</p></div>
<p>Amongst the photographs that Mdm Saraswathi had showed us, there were some of her wedding ceremony. Contrary to the rich and colourful festivities that typically surround an Indian wedding, Mdm Saraswathi&#8217;s wedding was very modest. Instead of a temple with a priest, her wedding was celebrated in a tent at the Seletar Camp, specially erected for this joyous occasion near her husband&#8217;s living quarters.</p>
<p>&#8220;(During the ceremony) we had followed our book, the tiripura, a book written by a sage to convey the knowledge. And somebody had read from that book. That was how we got married.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_924" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/009.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-924" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-924" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/009.jpg" alt="Mdm Saraswathi's brother on the eve of Thaipusam, preparing to carry the kavadi at the back for the ceremony the next morning. Photo credit: Mdm Saraswathi" width="500" height="382" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/009.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/009-300x229.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-924" class="wp-caption-text">Mdm Saraswathi&#8217;s brother on the eve of Thaipusam, preparing to carry the kavadi (behind them) for the ceremony the next morning. Photo credit: Saraswathi</p></div>
<p>Another eventful recollection she had at the camp was the preparation for her brother to carry the kavadi for Thaipusam, a Hindu celebration in honour of Lord Subramaniam. In the photo was her husband, uncle and brother on the eves of Thaipusam in their home, getting ready for the journey the next morning.</p>
<div id="attachment_925" style="width: 603px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/0011.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-925" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-925" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/0011.jpg" alt="During the Thaipusam procession where Hindhu devotees carry the kavadi. Photo credit: Mdm Saraswathi" width="593" height="450" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/0011.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/0011-300x227.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/0011-94x70.jpg 94w" sizes="(max-width: 593px) 100vw, 593px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-925" class="wp-caption-text">During the Thaipusam procession where Hindu devotees carry the kavadi. Photo credit: Saraswathi</p></div>
<p>When asked whether carrying the kavadi would be painful, she chuckled as she replied, &#8220;Actually, it would be, if you hadn&#8217;t followed the preparations properly. (The devotees carrying the kavadi) would fast for one week. You can take food only once a day in the evenings after your prayers.&#8221; The fasting devotees would be allowed to drink. But milk, she told us, is restricted because it is meant to be an offering to the God.</p>
<div id="attachment_928" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/IMG_3018.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-928" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-928" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/IMG_3018.jpg" alt="Wei Keong and Mdm Saraswathi outside her flat in Toa Payoh. Photo credit: SG Snaps" width="500" height="750" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/IMG_3018.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/10/IMG_3018-200x300.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-928" class="wp-caption-text">Wei Keong and Mdm Saraswathi outside her flat in Toa Payoh. Photo credit: SG Snaps</p></div>
<p>After our pleasant afternoon with Mdm Saraswathi, listening to her time-transporting stories of Seletar Camp, we thanked her for her time and exited her flat to the scenery of Toa Payoh today. The home in the black and white photographs of hers is so different from her current home. The times that we see in a single lifetime in Singapore has definitely changed, and we continue to wonder how the lives of people living here has changed too.</p>
<p>Written by Samantha Tio<br />
Edited by Tan Wei Keong</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toa Payoh: From Marshland to Satellite Neighbourhood</title>
		<link>/toa-payoh-from-marshland-to-satellite-neighborhood/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 01:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Old Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflection and Recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toa Payoh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1970s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HDB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neighbourhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playgrounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queen Elizabeth II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tree god]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The energetic buzz of the Toa Payoh Central was extremely effecting and perfect for the first neighbourhood to kick-start our photo-collection drive at Singapore Snaps. Toa Payoh Central has every conveniences to suit the quintessential middle-class Singaporean lifestyle &#8211; a train station linked to a bus interchange, a cozy public library, and a wide selection of eateries ranging from coffee [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The energetic buzz of the Toa Payoh Central was extremely effecting and perfect for the first neighbourhood to kick-start our photo-collection drive at Singapore Snaps. Toa Payoh Central has every conveniences to suit the quintessential middle-class Singaporean lifestyle &#8211; a train station linked to a bus interchange, a cozy public library, and a wide selection of eateries ranging from coffee shops, food kiosks to fast food restaurants and all the ubiquitous food chains. There are also supermarkets, mega-stationery-shop, banks and rows of shops selling clothes, gadgets, services and what-nots.</p>
<p><em>Mdm Sisilia Tan and company posing for a picture by the sculpture found in Toa Payoh Town Park with the estate in the backdrop. Photo: Sisilia Tan</em></p>
<p>Also located here is the headquarters of our nation&#8217;s Housing Development Board (HDB).  Situating the headquarters here is extremely apt for being the first town to be built ground-up by the board in 1968. With a neighbourhood population of close to 116,000 people, it is not a surprise that the town centre will always be crowded with people, especially during the evenings and weekends.</p>
<p>Through chatting with the local residents, we discovered the urban legends and quaint histories of this neighbourhood.</p>
<p><strong>1. Urban legend goes that there was an immutable “Tree God” which fell in a storm in September last year.</strong></p>
<p>Every morning, the SG Snaps team strolled past the site where the “Tree God” used to be &#8211; on the way from the train station to the community library. We were told about the lightning strike that brought down the tree said to be over 100 years old. It is with this curiosity that we searched for the site to pay tributes.</p>
<p>Upon quizzing a few of the shop owners in the vicinity, we were directed to a tightly barricaded site that seemed dilapidated and uncared for. The emptiness of the space was a huge departure from our imagination of the tree with majestic bark and extensive branches that shaded the temple that was beneath it.</p>
<div id="attachment_664" style="width: 339px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Tree-God_National-Archives.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-664" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-664 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Tree-God_National-Archives.jpg" alt="A photo from the 1970s of the sacred tree and its temple at Toa Payoh Central. Photo: National Archives of Singapore" width="329" height="508" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Tree-God_National-Archives.jpg 498w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Tree-God_National-Archives-194x300.jpg 194w" sizes="(max-width: 329px) 100vw, 329px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-664" class="wp-caption-text">A photo from the 1970s of the sacred tree and its temple at Toa Payoh Central. Photo: National Archives of Singapore, Source: Singapore Press Holdings</p></div>
<p>The site did exude a mystical charm which was even more resonant when we learned of the strange occurrences when the new town was constructed in 1965: The bulldozers that were tasked to flatten the area malfunctioned when they approached the tree. Workers who tried to fell the tree had also died mysteriously. The town planners then had to alter the layout of the shop houses to accommodate the tree in the centre. Isn&#8217;t it interesting how our urban development can be shaped by mysticism and superstition?</p>
<p><strong>2. Toa Payoh Public Library was one of the earliest full-time library to open after Queenstown.</strong></p>
<p>The location, prior to the opening of the library, was the Games Village which housed athletes for the 7<sup>th</sup> South East Asian Peninsula Games. It was the first regional sporting event ever held in the country in 1973.</p>
<div id="attachment_656" style="width: 485px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Toa-Payoh.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-656" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-656" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Toa-Payoh.jpg" alt="Photo: Chan Lee Shan" width="475" height="674" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Toa-Payoh.jpg 540w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Toa-Payoh-211x300.jpg 211w" sizes="(max-width: 475px) 100vw, 475px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-656" class="wp-caption-text">A portrait at the fountain in front of Toa Payoh Community Library. Photo: Chan Lee Shan</p></div>
<p>Before the amphitheatre in the front of the library was built, there was a huge water fountain where many of the residents gathered for photographs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_659" style="width: 624px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-659" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-659 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-1024x680.jpg" alt="The SG Snaps team (from left) Gracie, Stacy and Wei Keong at the cozy booth on the second floor of Toa Payoh Community Library. Photo: SG Snaps" width="614" height="408" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-1024x680.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-300x199.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-1800x1200.jpg 1800w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/end_2-1280x850.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 614px) 100vw, 614px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-659" class="wp-caption-text">The SG Snaps team (from left) Gracie, Stacy and Wei Keong at the cozy booth on the second floor of Toa Payoh Community Library. Photo: SG Snaps</p></div>
<p>Toa Payoh Community Library has got to be one of our favourite libraries visited. The library was streaming continuously with visitors over the weekend. Besides being a conducive air-conditioned haven for our tired volunteers to catch their breaths, the library staff there were simply endearing. <a href="/sunny-days-an-offbeat-meeting-at-the-toa-payoh-public-library/">Uncle Sunny</a> is one of them, along with the counter staff who would climb up and down the stairs assisting our requests. Huiyi and Shao, from the Arts and Culture team of the National Library Board, were the ones who made our 3-weeks residence at the library possible. We missed the friendly cleaning aunties whom we grew close to and felt so sorry when we had to leave for another library.</p>
<p><strong>3. Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II visited the flats in Toa Payoh twice in 1972 &amp; 2006.</strong></p>
<p>Ask any long-staying resident for a historical anecdote of Toa Payoh and they will definitely mention the visit of Queen Elizabeth II. The lucky then-boy-now-man visited by the Queen in 1972 is Mr Jerome Lim, writer of the blog &#8216;The Long Winding Road&#8217; which reminiscent intimately the personal histories of growing-up in Singapore.</p>
<div id="attachment_666" style="width: 394px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/queen-elizabeth-visits-toa-payoh.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-666" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-666" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/queen-elizabeth-visits-toa-payoh.jpg" alt="Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II on the rooftop of Toa Payoh's VIP Flat at Blk 53 Lorong 5, during her visit in 1972. Photo: www.toapayoh.com" width="384" height="278" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/queen-elizabeth-visits-toa-payoh.jpg 384w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/queen-elizabeth-visits-toa-payoh-300x217.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 384px) 100vw, 384px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-666" class="wp-caption-text">Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II on the rooftop of Toa Payoh&#8217;s VIP Flat at Blk 53 Lorong 5, during her visit in 1972. Photo: www.toapayoh.com</p></div>
<p>The Queen had visited Mr Lim’s 3-room flat &#8211; a VIP Flat with a rooftop viewing gallery, which sounds like the Pinnacle@Duxton of the 1970s. She returned to the estate 34 years later in 2006 during her Diamond Jubilee tour of the world. There must be a certain nostalgia and pride that our country holds for our history of being colonised.</p>
<p><strong> 4. How can we not possibly mention? The Dragon Playground, of course.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_651" style="width: 529px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-651" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-651" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground-732x1024.jpg" alt="Photo: Seow Shin Horng" width="519" height="726" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground-732x1024.jpg 732w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground-214x300.jpg 214w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dragon_playground.jpg 1040w" sizes="(max-width: 519px) 100vw, 519px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-651" class="wp-caption-text">Walking along the long &#8216;body&#8217; of the Dragon. Photo: Seow Shin Horng</p></div>
<p>I suppose, most heritage buffs in Singapore would know of the Dragon Playground along Lorong 6. The playground has become so iconic that it has inspired more replicas and reflections than the Merlion in the last 2 years.</p>
<div id="attachment_652" style="width: 567px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-652" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-652" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground-1024x730.jpg" alt="Photo: Seow Shin Horng" width="557" height="396" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground-1024x730.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground-300x213.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground-1280x913.jpg 1280w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/pelican_playground.jpg 1458w" sizes="(max-width: 557px) 100vw, 557px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-652" class="wp-caption-text">Digging sand with daddy at the Pelican Playground. Photo: Seow Shin Horng</p></div>
<div id="attachment_650" style="width: 480px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-650" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-650" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground-730x1024.jpg" alt="Photo: Seow Shin Horng" width="470" height="659" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground-730x1024.jpg 730w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground-213x300.jpg 213w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/dove_playground.jpg 1046w" sizes="(max-width: 470px) 100vw, 470px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-650" class="wp-caption-text">The Dove Playground. Photo: Seow Shin Horng</p></div>
<p>The Dragon Playground was part of a series of animal-inspired playground designed by the HDB in the 1970s. Other motifs include the Pelican, Dove and Elephant etc. In the collection of photographs received from the public, there were many cute kids portraits taken at these playgrounds. It is no doubt that these playgrounds have a prominent place in the childhood memories of Singaporeans who grew up during that era. Though there is another dragon playground in Ang Mo Kio, it is the one in Toa Payoh that retains the sand pit. A sand-filled playground was a common structure in most neighbourhoods, before boring rubber matting replaced the sand. What&#8217;s the fun if you can’t throw sand into the eyes of your enemy/crush ?</p>
<p><strong>5. Toa Payoh used to be a farmland</strong>.</p>
<p>Part of the old Toa Payoh came alive when we spent an afternoon with Mdm Lim Mui Tiang, a resident of Toa Payoh. Mdm Lim recounted where the farms were, and how the HDB flat she&#8217;s living in was previously a hill flattened for the construction of the town. At the age of six, she helped at her family farm with the harvesting of vegetables and feeding of the poultry. By seven, she was bringing water from the well. Though we probably have heard similar stories from the earlier generations many times, it is hard to imagine the same kind of hardship for any children growing up in modern Singapore.</p>
<div id="attachment_667" style="width: 490px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ToaPayoh1967.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-667" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-667" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ToaPayoh1967.jpg" alt="ToaPayoh1967" width="480" height="339" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ToaPayoh1967.jpg 480w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ToaPayoh1967-300x211.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-667" class="wp-caption-text">Aerial view of Toa Payoh taken in 1967. Photo: www.toapayoh.com</p></div>
<p>Toa Payoh has come a long way from its earliest histories of being made up of marshland and plantations. The name “Toa Payoh” means “big swamp”  in the Hokkien dialect. Walking down the concrete paths, watching people sip coffee from Starbucks, families pushing their children around in strollers and pedestrians burying their heads in their devices, it must be really astounding to witness such tremendous change within a single lifetime.</p>
<p>Written by Samantha Tio<br />
Edited by Tan Wei Keong</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visiting the Residents: Unearthing Photographs &#038; Personal Histories</title>
		<link>/visiting-the-residents-unearthing-photographs-personal-histories/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 15:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Toa Payoh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Updates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Door-to-door]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neighbourhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Being a relational art project with a tag line &#8220;Preserving Precious Memories&#8221;, it is important to us that we keep the element of interaction with the community. We strive to do this through door-to-door visits with the residents of the neighbouring HDB near the public library, where the team sets up the collection booth. With the involvement of student volunteers, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Being a relational art project with a tag line &#8220;Preserving Precious Memories&#8221;, it is important to us that we keep the element of interaction with the community.</p>
<p>We strive to do this through door-to-door visits with the residents of the neighbouring HDB near the public library, where the team sets up the collection booth. With the involvement of student volunteers, the project connects the residents with students of a younger generation, and engage meaningful conversations about personal histories and memories.</p>
<p>For the past three weeks, we have been collecting photographs from the residents, who we got to know better by talking to them about their memories, of a moment in time of the stories they captured with their photographs. Students from Hwa Chong Institute and Hougang Secondary School, as well as friends who participated in this journey, have been making their rounds together in the Toa Payoh neighbourhood. The photographs and stories they collected are nothing short of intriguing, informing and in fact, unexpected.</p>
<p>Student volunteers arrive in the afternoons after school, or on weekends to visit the neighbourhood either in pairs, or in small groups. Prior to heading out, they are briefed on their introduction of themselves and the project to the residents, and having positive attitudes throughout the visit. Should a resident be interested in learning more about the project, and in the event that the resident wishes to participate, volunteers may be invited into the resident&#8217;s home. While accepting the photo contributions, volunteers are encouraged to be curious and inquisitive so Contributors are encouraged to share their personal stories in relation to the photographs at hand.</p>
<div id="attachment_459" style="width: 658px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2948.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-459" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-459  " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2948.jpg" alt="The student volunteer team from Singapore Snaps taking part in a slightly uncommon volunteering endeavour." width="648" height="432" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2948.jpg 1800w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2948-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2948-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2948-1280x853.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 648px) 100vw, 648px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-459" class="wp-caption-text">The student volunteer team from Singapore Snaps taking part in a slightly uncommon volunteering endeavour.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_461" style="width: 658px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2961.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-461" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-461  " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2961.jpg" alt="The corridors of our HDBs may look similar, but each home holds stories waiting to be discovered - These are the stories our volunteers get access to when a willing resident opens the doors to let them in." width="648" height="432" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2961.jpg 1800w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2961-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2961-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_2961-1280x853.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 648px) 100vw, 648px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-461" class="wp-caption-text">The corridors of our HDBs may look similar, but each home holds stories waiting to be discovered &#8211; These are the stories our volunteers get access to when a willing resident opens the doors to let them in.</p></div>
<p>When a Contributor submits his or her photographs, we take great care in ensuring that the photographs are kept in its original condition until they are returned. These are the steps that we take:</p>
<p><strong>Step 1: We account for all the contributed photographs.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_463" style="width: 590px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0348.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-463" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-463 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0348.jpg" alt="Singapore Snaps Photo Archival 1" width="580" height="327" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0348.jpg 3840w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0348-300x168.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0348-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0348-1280x720.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-463" class="wp-caption-text">For each set of photographs collected, we have two types of calculations: 1) Total number of photos submitted 2) Of these, the total number of photos selected for scanning. This way, we ensure full accountability for the photos submitted.</p></div>
<p><strong>Step 2: We protect the photographs and albums with bubble wrap.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_471" style="width: 673px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0350.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-471" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-471 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0350.jpg" alt="Singapore Snaps Wrapping" width="663" height="374" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0350.jpg 3840w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0350-300x168.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0350-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/06/DSC_0350-1280x720.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 663px) 100vw, 663px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-471" class="wp-caption-text">Loose photographs and photo albums are wrapped in protective bubble wrap before delivering them to our professional scanning studio for digitising.</p></div>
<p><strong>Step 3: We deliver the package personally for scanning. Once scanning completes, the SG Snaps team returns the original photographs and albums to the contributor, together with a free personalised DVD containing the digitised photos.</strong></p>
<p>And that, folks, is what we do on a typical &#8220;workday&#8221; at SG Snaps. We have just finished our stint at the Toa Payoh library and will be at the Central Library and Bukit Merah library from 11 June onwards.</p>
<p>Thinking ahead, we wonder&#8230; how will the photographs collected at Bukit Merah differ from the contributions and stories in Toa Payoh? Will we see a greater variety of photographic types and content, or more similarities? How will our collections in Bukit Merah and Central Library shape the 3 animations? Join our journey, and we shall see!</p>
<p>Till then &#8211; Much Love &amp; Be Well.</p>
<p>Writen by Annette</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunny Days: An Offbeat Meeting at the Toa Payoh Public Library</title>
		<link>/sunny-days-an-offbeat-meeting-at-the-toa-payoh-public-library/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 05:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toa Payoh]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Finding sentimental moments was one of the things I was looking forward very much to when I embarked as a team member of SG Snaps, and yet, it seemed serendipitous that we should have had a visitor who turned out the be one of the most sentimental men I have ever met. He graced the team with both his sunshine [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Finding sentimental moments was one of the things I was looking forward very much to when I embarked as a team member of SG Snaps, and yet, it seemed serendipitous that we should have had a visitor who turned out the be one of the most sentimental men I have ever met. He graced the team with both his sunshine and his stories.</p>
<p>On day two at our booth, Uncle Sunny, 64, brought two very special albums containing greetings cards that he fatefully gave to his wife, Jessie, 60, every year for her birthdays and for their anniversaries. The giving is a mutual affair and Uncle Sunny stressed to me the importance of giving credit to this wife in this exchange.</p>
<p>The couple have been married for 37 years and as the years passed, Uncle Sunny&#8217;s gesture of romance never waived one bit. People express their love in many different ways and taking photographs of loved ones is just one form of expression. Uncle Sunny&#8217;s commitment in giving his wife greeting cards is another. &#8220;This is how I can be remembered by,&#8221; Uncle Sunny told me. It made me think about what we leave behind and how we remember precious moments.</p>
<p>Writen by Samantha</p>
<div id="attachment_431" style="width: 460px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/uncle-sunny.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-431" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-431" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/uncle-sunny.jpg" alt="Credits to Uncle Sunny of Toa Payoh Public Library" width="450" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/uncle-sunny.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/uncle-sunny-225x300.jpg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-431" class="wp-caption-text">Credits to Uncle Sunny of Toa Payoh Public Library</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
